http://www.ahta.com.au/privacy-policy-0

Cart
Member Login
Search
About usAbout the AHTA?Advertise with the AHTAAwardsCommitteesAdvocacy CommitteeCredentialing CouncilFinance Audit Risk and GovernanceManagement CommitteeMembership CommitteeProfessional Practice CommitteeState and Territory coordinatorsGovernanceAnnual General Meeting minutes (AGM)Annual ReportsHistoryHonoured membersOrganisational structureStaffInformation for patientsWhat is hand therapy?What is a Hand Therapist?Search for an Accredited Hand TherapistHand therapy conditionsPrivate health insurance rebatesMembershipBecome a memberBenefits for membersBUPAConsultation surveysFAQ'sFingerPrint newsletterGrantsHand Therapy Awareness WeekHTAW ideasMy portalOnline education resourcesPatient information handoutsPolicies, guidelines & position statementsSalary benchmarking reportVolunteering with the AHTAProfessional developmentCourse types and profilesCourse / event dates and bookingsCourse accreditationConferencesEducation cancellation policyOnline education resourcesPosition vacanciesWebinar recordingsWant to be a presenter of an AHTA Webinar?AHT credentialAccredited Hand Therapist (AHT)Applying for AHT Credential?Meet the councilOverseas-trained?ReaccreditingResearch & journalCurrent & published researchDistribution of research surveysEBSCO journal databaseElsevier (Science Direct) journal databaseMentorship in researchResearch portalResearch scholarship
ShopContact Us
Connect
Twitter
Facebook
Linkedin
Instagram
Privacy Policy
×
Login Or Join
User Login
E-mail: * Password: *
Create new account
Request new password
Our Commitment to Your Privacy
Your privacy is important to the Australian Hand Therapy Association (AHTA). As part of the normal operation of this site, the AHTA may collect certain information from you. This privacy policy details what information the AHTA collects, how it uses that information and what your rights are regarding any information that you supply. The AHTA is subject to the requirements of applicable Australian law and strives to meet the requirements of the Australian Privacy Principles.
Your information
You can choose to provide as much or as little information as you like, although we require minimum information to provide you with access to our site. What you provide is your choice.
The AHTA will under no circumstances sell or rent any personal information that you supply to us to any third party. The AHTA has partnerships with commercial organisations and those partners will, from time to time, request that the AHTA send information to people on the AHTA database as part of the partnership. Any AHTA or partner information is sent by the AHTA and data is not provided to the third party. In short, information you supply to the AHTA stays with the AHTA. The AHTA may disclose personal information to the following third parties to satisfy standard operating procedures of the AHTA:
IT service providersPrinters that print and distribute our publications and marketing material
By using this site and the AHTA’s services, you acknowledge and accept that it will use your personal data as set out in this privacy policy. If you do not accept this privacy policy, please immediately stop using the site and/or the AHTA’s services or any part of them. Please note, you will not be able to register or purchase anything further using this site.
This site may include links to third-party websites. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. We strongly recommend you read the privacy policy of every website you visit.
AHTA is responsible for your personal data. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, including requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the office at enquire@ahta.coma.u
AHTA follows the principles laid out in data protection legislation when handling personal data. These principles require personal data to be:
Processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent mannerCollected only for specified, explicit and legitimate purposesAdequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which it is processedNot kept in a form which permits identification of data subjects for longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the data is processedProcessed in a manner that ensures its security using appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damageNot transferred to another country without appropriate safeguards being in placeMade available to data subjects and allow data subjects to exercise certain rights in relation to their personal data
The AHTA is also responsible and accountable for ensuring that it can demonstrate compliance with the data protection principles listed above.
Collecting Information
The AHTA may collect, use and store different kinds of personal data about you. It collects this data about you when you access and use the site and its services as follows:
Register an accountLeave a commentPlace an advertisementRegister for a course/event/conferenceBuy a productContact the AHTASubscribe to the AHTA’s communications (Newsletter, Enews etc)Manage your communication preferencesMake a payment
The AHTA may hold the following information about you:
Name, address, telephone number(s)Date of birthEmail addressTransaction details associated with services we have provided to youAdditional information provided to and by youInformation you have provided to us via member surveys
The AHTA may also collect, use and share aggregated data such as demographic or statistical data. Aggregated data is obtained from your personal data but is not considered personal data under data protection law as it does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For eg, the AHTA may aggregate data about your use of the site to calculate the statistics around users accessing a specific page or item. The AHTA may aggregate data that it collects through your use of the site in order to produce certain benchmarking reports. However, if the AHTA combines or connects aggregated data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, the AHTA treats the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.
Access to Personal Information
You have the right to review and alter any personal membership information that the AHTA stores. It is your information, so you should be the person that controls it. Should you wish to access this information please contact the office at enquire@ahta.com.au
To change your personal information, you must login to your account with your unique login and password via the AHTA website www.ahta.com.au
Opt-Out
By choosing to register on the AHTA website or as a member of the AHTA, you may receive information from us about membership, AHTA services, member notices, publications, and communications relevant to your use of the site and your AHTA membership. The AHTA uses this method to communicate quickly with you. You have the right to refuse inclusion on a mailing list. You can make a request to remove your email address from a mailing list by updating your Mailing Preferences in your account profile.
From time to time, the AHTA arranges mailings using the contact information you have provided, from its business partners (including corporate partners and endorsed product manufacturers/suppliers). These mailings aim to provide you with information and benefits available to you,
If you do not wish to receive information from AHTA's business partners, you should advise the office at enquire@ahta.com.au.
Your personal password to access the AHTA website protects your privacy. We recommend that you do not disclose, share or reveal this password to any other individual.
Change of Purpose
It is not anticipated that any information will be disclosed to overseas recipients. If this were to change this page will be updated.
From time to time, the AHTA may decide to collect different kinds of information. When this occurs, the AHTA will update this privacy page.
AHT Membership
If you decide to become an Accredited Hand Therapist as awarded by the AHTA, and we hope that you do, the AHTA will ask you for additional personal details. You may also opt to provide the AHTA with more information such as special interest areas you may have. Relevant information is disclosed to the public on the internet via the AHTA's 'Find a Therapist' online directory only. Whether you decide to use this service is your choice.
Security
Your information is stored on AHTA's server located in a secure data housing facility. While, it is important to recognise that "perfect security" does not exist on the internet, the AHTA is committed to using industry standard mechanisms to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers.
Cookies
As part of the normal operation of this site, your internet browser will be sent a "cookie" (a temporary internet file). This cookie enhances the site's functionality with features such as membership logon and electronic ordering. By itself, this cookie can only identify your computer to AHTA’s server; it is not used to identify you personally.
Credit Card Information
The AHTA does not permanently store credit card information anywhere on this site.
AHTA Members Privacy
The AHTA has a strong commitment to protecting your privacy and ensuring the confidentiality and security of personal information provided to the AHTA by you. The AHTA is required to comply with the Privacy Act 1988 as amended by the Privacy Amendment (Enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012 which came into effect in March 2014. Click here to access full details: Australia's Privacy Act
Information you have provided to the AHTA is used to:
Process applications and renewals and to update your membership details and profile informationNotify members and the public that you have met our requirements for credentialingProvide information to consumers and others on the availability of Hand Therapy servicesConduct market research to identify and analyse the ongoing needs of AHTA membersEnsure compliance with the AHTA's Constitution and By-LawsProvide you with AHTA publications and informationProvide you with access to and information about current and future member benefits
Consent
You acknowledge and agree that by providing your personal and/or sensitive information to the AHTA that the Association and our corporate partners and each of their officers, employees, contractors and volunteers are permitted to collect, store, use and disclose your personal information in the manner set out in this privacy policy and in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles.
Contact Us
Please do not hesitate to contact us if you have a concern or issue in relation to how we collect, store, use or disclose your personal information by clicking here: Contact Us
Our Partners
Working together with AHTA
Get In Touch
Make an enquiry
Membership
Why Join the AHTA? Member Portal Reaccrediting
Your Development
Course & Events Meetings and Conferences Regional and Remote Grants CPD Diary
Quick Links
Shop Place a Position Vacancy Library Research Portal FAQ's
© 2020 Australian Hand Therapy Association
All prices are in Australian Dollars ($AUD)
Complaints & FeedbackInternational & Australian ConferencesPrivacy PolicyTerms and ConditionsTel: 08 9778 9070
